allinahealth.org 2013-11-06

# Privacy policy for allinahealth.org

Allinahealth.org is the corporate website for Allina Health. As an integrated health care delivery system, we are both experienced in and strongly believe in protecting the right of privacy for patients. Our policies and practices are guided by this underlying conviction. 

We do not share personally identifiable information submitted to allinahealth.org unless we are authorized to do so, or we are required to do so by law. If you are an Allina Health patient, please see our notice of privacy practices. 

Section 1. Registration  
Section 2. Message boards as public forums  
Section 3. Mailing lists  
Section 4. Links to other sites  
Section 5. Website statistics and reports   
Section 6. Security  
Section 7. Children's guidelines  
Section 8. Contacting allinahealth.org  
Section 9. MyChart records

## Section 1. Registration

Some features of our site require users to register and provide certain personal information. If you are not comfortable with this, you can choose not to use this part of the site. When the registration form is presented to you, we clearly indicate what information is required for the particular feature, and what information is optional. 

Allinahealth.org site administrators have access to information you provide when you register but this is for purposes of administering these public services. 

When you register for services other than email publications, you will be asked to choose a user name and a password. This password ensures your identify and allows you to change your personal information and options. All registration information, beyond registering for email publications, is sent encrypted via secure socket layers (ssl), so that information cannot be intercepted and read. 

If they so choose, users may provide us with additional demographic and related information. This data helps us understand who our users are so that we can develop new features and services. We do not share information provided in this manner that can identify individuals without an individual's consent, unless required by law. 

You can be removed from our registration database at any time by contacting us. 

Return to top.

## Section 2. Message boards as public forums

We require all users to identify themselves and register with the site prior to participation on a message board. Users are allowed to select their own screen name. This registration process is private and protected. 

However, the message boards are public forums; any information that is disclosed during these forums is public information. Thus, please exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

For more about using message boards and other interactive services, see section 6 of allinahealth.org's terms and conditions of use. 

Return to top.

## Section 3. Mailing lists

This site offers features delivered by email. This service is maintained and administered by allinahealth.org staff. We do not sell or otherwise share these email lists with others. 

You can remove your name from any lists you have registered for, or add your name to additional lists from [our health e-newsletters page](http://ww2.allina.com/ac/email.nsf/subscribe?OpenForm). 

Return to top.

## Section 4. Links to other sites

This site contains links to other sites that we believe may be valuable to our users. While we try to review each site prior to providing a link, allinahealth.org is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. 

Return to top.

## Section 5. Website statistics and reports

We do not track information on a specific individual. We do, however, track and report aggregate statistics regarding usage of allinahealth.org. This is required to see what areas of our site are popular and what areas and processes need improvement. 

Specifically, we track total number of… 

  * pages viewed on our site
  * visitors to the site and/or a specific section of the site
  * repeat visitors to the site and/or a specific section of the site
  * new visitors to the site and/or a specific section of the site

This aggregate data may be shared internally or externally with organizations similar to ours. 

**Cookies** \-- Some of the information that we are seeking is gathered by using "cookies." A cookie is a text file that a web server stores on your computer. This text file is used to track information about the activity that particular browser performs on the web server. In our case, we use it to track total number of unique visitors, total number of repeat visitors, and total number of new visitors to our site. 

You may set up your browser to alert you when a site is using a cookie. You can then either proceed, or disable the cookie through your options or preference or similar section of your browser. 

Other information that we track that does not require cookies is total number of pages viewed and total number of visits. 

Return to top.

## Section 6. Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

Return to top.

## Section 7. Children's guidelines

This site does not direct content to children under the age of 13, nor do we permit registration of or collect personal information about children younger than 13. 

Return to top.

## Section 8. Contacting allinahealth.org

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can email us. You may also send mail to this address:  
Allinahealth.org  
Allina Health Web and Interactive Marketing  
Mail Route 10103  
2925 Chicago Avenue  
Minneapolis, MN 55407-1321  

Return to top.

## Section 9. MyChart records

As we provide your health care, we maintain documentation of your medical history, current conditions, treatment plan and all treatments given, including the results of all tests, procedures and therapies. MyChart is an internet application that enables a patient to have secure web-based access to selected medical information about the patient. 

MyChart also allows secure electronic messaging with Allina Health. A message you send via MyChart may be made part of your permanent medical record at the discretion of the physician. Once it is made part of your record, it will be accessible to current and future Allina Health personnel who participate in your care. 

Individuals who are enrolled to use MyChart agree to use MyChart as their primary means to obtain the results of laboratory test performed for such patients at participating Allina Health facilities. 

### Your security responsibilities

When you initially enroll to use MyChart, you will be given an access code. With that code, you will be able to create a MyChart ID and password. This ID and password will allow you, or anyone else who has the ID and password, to view your medical information, submit comments that may become part of your record, and communicate with your health care team as if that person were you. 

For this reason, it is important that you keep your access code, MyChart ID and password completely confidential. You should prevent disclosure of your access code, ID or password, and you should change your password if you believe that your security may have been compromised. In addition, you should change your password regularly to help maintain the security of your account. You can change your password online at any time by logging into MyChart and choosing the “Change Password” option. 

**If you have any questions about the security of your password** , please MyChart Support at 1-855-551-6555, 24 hours a day, seven days a week.

### MyChart messaging

MyChart messaging should never be used for urgent matters. The anticipated turnaround time for response to electronic messages is two business days. Therefore, **for all urgent medical matters, contact your physician’s office by phone, go to an emergency room, or dial 911**. 

All communications between you and your Allina Health health care team using MyChart are carried over a secure, encrypted connection. While you may receive internet email messages notifying you of new messages in your MyChart Inbox, these emails will not contain any confidential medical information. However, any person with access to the email account to which such messages are sent will be able to see the notifications. 

### Restrictions

MyChart does not reproduce a patient's entire medical record online, but instead provides access to selected information such as prescriptions, basic laboratory results, summary medical history, appointments, and other such information. Even within categories of information that are generally made available through MyChart, posting of information is strictly at the discretion of the individual physician. 

To comply with applicable laws and regulations, Allina Health provides parents and legal guardians with limited proxy access to minors' health information through MyChart. The scope of such access will vary depending on the age and legal status of the minor. 

Allina Health reserves the right to terminate access to MyChart at any time, for any reason or no reason. In addition, a user's access to MyChart will be terminated of Allina Health determines that the user has misused or abused the system, violated any applicable terms of use, or used the system for purposes other than those for which it is intended to be used. 

Return to top.
